# **JESUS MANUEL ORTIZ**

jesusmoh89@gmail.com | 786 630 5797 | www.linkedin.com/in/jesusmoh | Miami, FL 33134 | Visit my site

#### **SUMMARY**

Software Engineer with over a decade of experience in the IT field, specializing in IT Solutions for more than 10 years and expertise in Fintech, Retail, and IT Healthcare industries, where I have experience in roles such as Sys Admin.

## **HARD SKILLS**

Jira | AWS | Cloud | Ngnix | EC2 | DevOps | Confluence | Database Design | S3 | Kubernetes | Docker | Linux | Docker-Compose | Hyper-V | RAID | DHCP | FTP | TeamViewer | ETL | VSCode | PCI | Serverless | On-premises | ERP | Servers | ETL.

#### SOFT SKILLS

Team Player | Multitasking | Self-Taught Learner | Spanish Speaker | Effective Leadership in Small Teams | Tolerance

# **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

FISERV (Global Fintech) | Senior Software Development Engineer (II) | Team size 5 | May 2021 – Dec 2023 | U.S.A

- As part of the **FSwitchUY team**, we prioritized maintaining robust solutions through continuous updates and timely resolution of *critical security issues*. This, combined with other key objectives, enabled the company's sustained growth across AWS Cloud.
- Monitor the health of critical computer systems.
- Operating system deployment tools with docker.
- Provide users with basic software training.
- Onboarding process.

SISNET (Software Provider for Retail/Logistic) | Senior Software Development Engineer | Team size 6 | Nov 2017 - May 2021 | URU

- Implemented Java backend solutions (Rest/SOAP APIs) using Jakarta, Payara Micro, Cache and Hibernate resulting in a 40% improvement in API response time, and enhanced system POS terminal performance.
- Operating system deployment tools with docker.
- Tasks include network printer support, daily server backups, document, and monitor issues, maintaining corporate compliance
  and documentation; and configuring, deploying, and supporting IT connectivity to broadcast equipment throughout the studio
  and transmitter sites.

SASA (Retail auto-parts) | IT technical leader & Senior Software Development Engineer | Team size 6 | Sep 2014 – Nov 2017 | CUB

- Configured and planned strategic infrastructure upgrades for 14 on-premises dependencies, delivering a highly available solution that leveraged Hyper-V, Active Directory, RAID, Group policy creation, and HP ProLiant servers, achieving a 99.00% increase in system uptime.
- Achieved a 70% decrease in processing time for ETL tasks related to stock status processing using Pentaho and Scala to support parallel processing of large datasets.
- Experience with Windows 10\11and Office 365, including OneDrive, Teams, and SharePoint.

### **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Science in Software Engineering, Technological University of Havana (CUJAE), Cuba, September 2009 – July 2014

# **CERTIFICATIONS AND BADGES**

AWS Certified Developer Associate | AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate | AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner

### **RESEARCH PROJECTS AND INITIATIVES**

PHP | WooCommerce | Wix | Node.js | Al/ML | HL7 | HCE | PCI | Java | Android | Kotlin | Shopizer | GCP | Pentaho | Scala